Presenter: Our first caller this evening is Andy.
Hi, Andy.
What’s your tip for being positive?
Andy: Hello.
Well, I think it’s very important to live in the present and not in the past.
Don’t think about mistakes you made in the past – you can’t change things now.
The important thing is to think about how you can do things better now and in the future.
Presenter: Thank you, Andy.
And now we have another caller.
What’s your name, please?
Julie: Hi, my name’s Julie.
My tip is think positive thoughts, not negative ones.
We all have negative thoughts sometimes, but when we start having them,
we need to stop and try to change them into positive ones.
Like, if you have an exam tomorrow and you start thinking, ‘I’m sure I’ll fail,’ then you’ll fail the exam.
So you need to change that negative thought to a positive thought.
Just think to yourself, ‘I’ll pass that exam’.
I do this and it usually works.
Presenter: Thank you, Julie.
And our next caller is Martin.
Hi, Martin.
Martin: Hi.
Um, my tip is don’t spend a lot of time following the news online or on TV.
It’s always bad news and it just makes you feel depressed.
Read a book or listen to your favourite music instead, and you won’t feel so bad.
Presenter: Thanks, Martin. Good tip!
And our next caller is Miriam.
Miriam?
Miriam: Hi.
Presenter: Hi, Miriam.
What’s your tip?
Miriam: Every week, make a list of all the good things that happened to you,
on your phone or on a piece of paper.
Then if you’re feeling a bit sad or depressed, read the list and it’ll make you feel better.
Presenter: Thanks, Miriam.
And our last call is from Michael.
Hi, Michael.
We’re listening.
Michael: Hi. I think it’s good to try to use positive language when you speak to other people.
You know, if your friend has a problem, don’t say, ‘I’m sorry’ or ‘Oh, poor you.’
Say something positive, like ‘Don’t worry! Everything’ll be OK.’
That way, you’ll make the other person think more positively about their problem.
Presenter: Thank you, Michael.
Well, that’s all we’ve got time for.
A big thank you to all our callers.